<!-- Current Configuration Guide -->
<glossary><title>Current Configuration Guide - Glossary</title>
<glossdiv><title>Server Configuration</title>
<glossentry id="logfile">
<glossterm>log_file</glossterm>
<glossdef><para><emphasis>OPTIONAL</emphasis>
This specifies the log file Current should attempt to use
if the apache_log_file file is not writable.  In versions prior to 1.3, was the
only log file used by Current.</para>
</glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="loglevel">
<glossterm>log_level</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This tells the server what level of detail to log at; the
default level is VERBOSE (1).  This entry in the config file should be an
integer between zero (0) and ten (10) inclusive.</para>
</glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="serversecret">
<glossterm>server_secret</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This entry contains a <quote>secret</quote> string which is
used to generate system IDs for client machines.  If this string is changed,
all clients will have to re-register with the Current server before they will
be recognized as authorized clients.  This value must be changed, and should
be kept confidential for your site.</para>
</glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="serverid">
<glossterm>server_id</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This is a string that denotes the identity of the Current
server; it is not necessarily related to the hostname of the machine or to
anything else, but is simply a random string.  It is used in determining
if a given client is authorized to access this server, along with the
server_secret entry.</para>
</glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="privacystatement">
<glossterm>privacy_statement</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This is a message sent to the client when
<command>rhn_register</command> is run on the client against the Current
server.  It is free-text, and can be multiple lines long.  It should be
enclosed in quotes to ensure proper parsing of the configuration file.
</para>
</glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="welcomemessage">
<glossterm>welcome_message</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This is a free-form string which is a brief message sent to the
clients when <command>rhn_register</command> is run on the client against the
Current server.  It can be multiple lines long.
</para>
</glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="validchannels">
<glossterm>valid_channels</glossterm>
<glossdef><para><emphasis>DEPRECATED</emphasis>
This is a list if channel labels for valid channels served by
this instance of Current.  Please note:  this is not a list of channel section
names; it is a list of the labels of each section, found within the channel
section of the configuration file.  As of versions after 1.5.0, Current no
longer tracks channel information in the configuration file.
</para>
</glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="currentdir">
<glossterm>current_dir</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This is the location where all the database files, RPM headers,
and RPM symlinks will be kept.  This directory tree needs to be readable by
the user under which Apache normally runs.
</para></glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="apacheconfigfile">
<glossterm>apache_config_file</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This is the file to create with the Apache configuration bits
that enable the Current server.  This file should be included in Apache's main
configuration file with the line:
<screen>
Include &lt;filename&gt;
</screen>
</para></glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="accesstype">
<glossterm>access_type</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This parameter determines if permissions should be checked on
a user, group, or world basis.  Permission checking will be added to later
versions; this parameter is not yet used.  Valid values are <quote>user</quote>
<quote>group</quote>, and <quote>world</quote>.</para></glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="accessarg">
<glossterm>access_arg</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This parameter is used when access_type is either user or
group; it specifies the name of the user / group to use for permission
checking.</para></glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="dbtype">
<glossterm>db_type</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>
This designates the specific database backend that the server should use.  As
of recent 1.5.x releases and snapshots, the only valid value is "postgres".
In future versions, we hope to allow a minimum of "postgres" and "sqlite" for
PostgreSQL and SQLite backends respectively, and perhaps other contributed
database backends.
</para></glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="dbuser">
<glossterm>db_user</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This is the name of the database user that the server should
connect to the backend with.  This user must be created within the database,
and does not necessarily have any relationship to system users.
</para></glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="dbpass">
<glossterm>db_pass</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>
This is the password to use when initiating the database connection.  The
password (or pass phrase) cannot contain any escaped characters or
whitespace characters.  This is not due to restrictions by the databasse
backends but to the way the options within the Current server are parsed.  Yes,
having this password in cleartext in a configuration file can be dangerous;
hopefully we'll be able to cone up with a way to make it less dangerous.
Suggestions welcome.</para></glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="dbname">
<glossterm>db_name</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This is the database name to connect to.  In the Oracle world,
this is referred to a SID.  This database must be created by the user; it will
be populated with tables by the <command>cinstall initdb</command> command and
with data by <command>cadmin</command> commands.
</para></glossdef>
</glossentry>
<glossentry id="dbhost">
<glossterm>db_host</glossterm>
<glossdef><para>This is the hostname on which the database backend is running.
We highly recommend that the server and database be running on the same host
and that the value "localhost" be used here; we have not yes tested running
the server and database on separate hosts.
</para></glossdef>
</glossentry>
</glossdiv>


</glossary>
