
<!-- Current Installation Guide -->
<chapter><title>Installation Guide</title>
<section id="intro"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>
This document will guide you through the steps required to install a
functioning 1.6-series Current Server.  Regular maintenance of the server will
be covered later; the beginning portions of this document will only cover the 
steps required to get to a point where you have a valid Current server instance
responding to client registration and update requests.
</para>
<para>
Please note that Current (and up2date itself) are moderately advanced systems
administration topics.  If you aren't comfortable with tar, RPM, general
systems administration, and similar topics, you probably shouldn't be using
this software.  Although we want as large a user base as possible, and we hate 
discouraging people, this software can very easily destroy data and disable 
systems if it is not set up and used correctly.
</para>
<para>
You should also note that Current is still in very active development, most
especially with the 1.7 series; the 1.6 series has proven relatively stable, so
if you require stability, you should probably use a 1.6.x release.  If you
elect to proceed with the development version, you should be prepared to
encounter bugs, and willing to report them to the mailing list.
</para>
<para>
Bug reports should include any and all tracebacks, the version of up2date (or
rhn_register) and Current you are experiencing the problems with, and wherever
possible log extracts showing the failure.  You may also be asked
to submit your config file for the server and details on what packages are in
your database(s).
</para>
<para>
Between full releases (1.4 to 1.6 or similar), the release notes or README will
include any changes or minor incompatibilities.  You should definitely review
the example config file (<filename>current.conf</filename>) between
snapshots for changes, and you will almost certainly need to recreate your 
databases.  As of 1.0, Current records database versions, and will complain if
you attempt to run the server with an out-of-date database.
</para>
</section>
<section id="requirements"><title>Hardware and Software Prerequisites</title>
<para>
Your first concern is server hardware robustness.  The machines currently used
by the developers for testing minor and major releases are P4's running
between 1 and 3 GHz with 256 MB to 1 GB of RAM.  You will also 
need sufficient disk space to contain full trees of all the packages you wish
to update automatically, with an additional 50 - 100 MB for database overhead
per tree.  The full Red Hat 7.2 tree is roughly 2.5 GB and the updates for
7.2 are an additional 2.1 GB.  Red Hat Linux 7.1 is slightly smaller, but you
should probably plan on about 5 - 7 GB per tree (which includes the space for
the updates) for full Red Hat Linux trees, or trees of comparable size.  In
general, a good quality midrange server will provide you with the horsepower
you need for an average Current installation.
</para>
<para>
Secondly, you will need clients on the network; having an update server is sort
of pointless if you don't have anything to update.  :)  For Current, you will
need any version of Red Hat Linux, Red Hat Enterprise Linux or Fedora Core 
with up2date between versions 2.7 and 4.3 and all of up2date's
dependencies.
</para>
<para>
For version 1.6 you will also need the Apache web server, and one of the 
supported databases.  For 1.6 these are PostgreSQL, SQLite, and MySQL.
According to very 
preliminary test results, you should still be able to server normal web pages
from this Apache server after installing Current, but please don't try this on
a production server, as we can't guarantee that.
</para>
</section>
<section id="installing"><title>Installing Current</title>
<para>
There are two methods for installing the Current package; the method you choose
will depend on how you downloaded Current and how comfortable you are with
third-party RPM packages.  The developers, of course, highly recommend
downloading and installing with RPMs, as it's much easier than dealing with
the tarball.
</para>
<para>
The recommended method, again, is installing with the provided RPM packages.
To install Current with this method, simply download the RPM to your hard
drive, and issue an <command>rpm -ihv &lt;<filename>filename</filename>&gt;</command>
and watch the package get installed for you.  Make sure you get all of 
Current's requirements installed.  Next, you also need to use RPM, Up2date, or Yum to install a database Current can use.  Red Hat products come
with PostgreSQL and MySQL.  SQLite and the SQLite python bindings can be found
as RPMS from the Current web site.  See the documentation for each database
to get it installed and configured.  You can now skip down to the
section entitled <quote>Configuring Current</quote>.
</para>
<para>
To install using the tarball, download the tarball and unpack it.  This will
(should) create a directory called <filename>current-${version}/</filename> (e.g. <filename>
current-1.5.3/</filename>) in the
directory you unrolled the tarball from.  Inside this directory are several
<filename>.py</filename> files, an example configuration file, and the 
control executables <filename>cadmin</filename> and <filename>cinstall</filename>.  
First, copy all the <filename>.py</filename> files to 
<filename>/usr/share/current</filename>.  
The <filename>cadmin</filename> and <filename>cinstall</filename>
files should be copied to somewhere in root's path, probably 
<filename>/usr/sbin</filename> or <filename>/sbin</filename>.  Finally, you'll
need to create an <filename>/etc/current</filename> directory, and copy the
example configuration file (<filename>current.conf</filename>) there.
</para>
<para>
At this point, you need to install other requirements for Current.  If you 
can handle installing Current from a tarball then installing these should be
fairly simple.  Current requires the Apache web server, the mod_ssl module, 
the mod_python module, Red Hat's <filename>rpm-python</filename> package,
and a database.  Supported databases are PostgreSQL, SQLite, and MySQL.
</para>
<para>
Current is now installed in your system, but is not 
configured or otherwise usable.  On to configuration!
</para>
</section>
</chapter>
